# Aiyeniko Tomi Peter

# **Software Engineer / Frontend Engineer**

## tomiaiyeniko@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/Tomi-pter, LinkedIn: Tomi Aiveniko - LinkedIn, Portfolio: tomipter.com

A front-end developer and web accessibility advocate with 3+ years of experience that is highly adept at working both independently and collaborating in a team to build accessible and responsive web interfaces.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Frontend Engineer**

April 2021 - Present

# FStackDev, Abuja (Remote)

- Assisted in building and maintaining scalable, fully responsive and accessible websites/webapps for 20+ businesses and clients.
- Worked hand-in-hand with the back-end engineering team and design team in structuring and building websites/webapps to satisfy the needs of the client.
- Wrote automated tests using Jest, React testing library and Cypress ensuring 100% bug free shipping and deployment of production code.
- Collaborated with the backend team to integrate internal APIs and internal tooling applications.

## **Frontend Engineer (Contract)**

August 2022 - October 2022

# **DellMarvis Smart Technologies Ltd. (Remote)**

• I orchestrated, developed and launched the frontend infrastructure, design and functionality for DellMarvis' website using Nextjs, GSAP, Styled-Components, React-Leaflet and Formik.

### **Software Engineer**

January 2020 - March 2021

## NCPC (Nigerian Christian Pilgrims Commission), Abuja

- Developed a portal for pilgrimage application and interview scheduler that optimized pilgrimage applications and interview steps by over 50%.
- Implemented front-end technical solutions to meet project requirements.

## **Frontend Developer**

July 2019 - December 2019

#### Zkyte Technologies, Abuja

- Collaborated with the design team to take client wireframes from conception to implementation.
- Worked in an Agile, collaborative space to receive design requirements, and test applications.
- Conducted research and assisted with new business scoping efforts, resulting in the acquisition of 7 new clients

## **Frontend Engineer (Intern)**

March 2019 - July 2019

#### **FStackDev**

- Assisted in migrating legacy code to modern day standards.
- Assisted in removing bootstrap from company stack and moving to modern day css, thereby eliminating dead code and reducing bundle size by 20%.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Stack and Libraries**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Styled-Components, TailwindCSS, Redux/Redux Toolkit, Git/GitHub, REST APIs, GraphQL, GSAP, Framer-motion, SCSS/SASS, Leaflet.js, Chart.js, Figma, Webpack, Jest, React-Testing-Library, Cypress.

Skills: Communication, accessibility optimization, Search engine optimization, Googling, Test Automation.

Languages: English.

#### **EDUCATION**

Landmark University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc), Computer Science